# **Kyle Runge**

# Full Stack Developer

(618) 317-2429 | krunge1@hotmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS, SQL | Frameworks/Libraries: Flask, Jinja2, Bcrypt, Express, NodeJS, React, Spring, JPA, Hibernate, Tomcat, Apache, Maven, NPM Bootstrap | Design Methodologies: Model View Controller (MVC) architecture | Databases: MySQL, NoSql, MongoDB | Tools: MySQL Workbench, Spring Tool Suite, Spring Boot, Postman, REST API, JSON, AWS(EC2), Git, Github, Spreadsheet Server, Microsoft Query, ODBC, PowerBI

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

AUDIT MANAGER GitHub: Audit Manager

AuditManager is a website application designed to facilitate financial audit teams in managing and organizing their audit requests efficiently. It allows entities to view requested items with due dates, upload required documentation, and track request statuses. The MVP focuses on showcasing my OOP skillset and includes user authentication, full CRUD functionality for request items, and a comment section for team communication. The website is built using Java with the Spring framework, MySQL for the database and relies on Bootstrap for front-end styling. Future plans involve user base splitting, audit reporting, and template building for audits, enhancing the platform's capabilities and user experience.

BLIND DATE GitHub: Blind Date

Blind Date is a group project that takes a unique approach to the usual dating website. The website requires your group of friends to recommend blind dates for you rather than you selecting your own dates. The website is devloped using JavaScript with the MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js), along with CSS styling using Tailwind CSS. There is full CRUD functionality to each profile and user login and registration with validations. My role was focused on the backend activity primarily and supported with rendering information in the JSX files on the front-end.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### HELMKAMP CONSTRUCTION CO.

2021-Present

Commercial general contractor working in industrial, building, and life science market segments with \$50m+ in revenue <a href="Controller">Controller</a>

- Created intranet websites which included power automate workflows and dynamic data feeds.
- Lead technology improvements with third party providers.
- Supported field team with errors on proprietary FileMaker based systems.
- Developed SQL queries to generate KPI dashboards and ad hoc reporting
- Act as lead device manager and support hardware and software issues as they arise for the organization
- Leveraged existing software packages to streamline accounting processes and develop additional efficiencies; positioning the department for growth without the need for added headcount

FACILISGROUP 2018-2021

Software as a service provider working in the promotional products industry from startup to just under \$20m in revenue <u>Vice President of Finance | Director of Finance | Accounting/Data Manager</u>

- Led the conversion of multiple platforms and software business tools into a single Microsoft ecosystem. The conversion included multiple levels of department use case testing and training development.
- Procured and setup workstations for new hires and employees.
- Effectively managed a rapidly growing team within the Finance and HR divisions
- Lead Due Diligence of the subsidiary for a successful IPO of the parent company on the AIM stock exchange

MAJOR BRANDS 2018

Beer, liquor, and wine wholesale distributor with \$400m+ in revenue

## Financial Analyst

- Developed templates for the accounts payable OCR that was a portion of a larger ERP transition.
- Supported finance leadership in decisions with new ERP platform.
- Leveraged excel add-ons and data pulls from existing sources to increase month end processes, saving a half day each month in my role.
- Pulled vendor and supplier details from 4 separate software systems to establish import for new ERP system

# FACILISGROUP 2014-2018

## Partner Development Coordinator

- Solely responsible for supporting a user base of 500 users with tier 1 and 2 support.
- Worked directly with development team to troubleshoot and resolve issues requiring code changes.
- Active in testing end user functionality of iterations during the software launch life cycle.
- Leveraged my knowledge of the software from my support activity to train administrative teams to use best practices within the platform and minimize user errors.
- Worked with the development team to integrate a new support platform and knowledge base.

## **EDUCATION**

- Full Stack Software Developer | Certificate, Coding Dojo Bootcamp Python, Java, MERN Full Stacks
- **Community Bankers School** | Certificate, Community Bankers Association of Illinois Focus on Management and Leadership
- Accounting | BS, Southern Illinois University Edwardsville Bachelor of Science in Accountancy